<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geoffrey&#39;s travel blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Geoffrey&#39;s travel blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middle Atlas</title>
      <link>/2019/06/08/the-middle-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/08/the-middle-atlas/</guid>
      <description>We took another trip outside of Fes today, this time to the Middle Atlas Mountains. We were the only ones on the tour. This was a visit to an area which is not really geared for tourism but we got to see how people live in small town Morocco. In the first tow we visited a cave which was the traditional home of a Berber family. The family have since incorporated it into their house built on top of the cave but it was neat to see inside, the man who lived there was very welcoming and showed us the rugs his grandmother makes by hand and gave us some mint tea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moroccan cooking</title>
      <link>/2019/06/07/moroccan-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/07/moroccan-cooking/</guid>
      <description>Today we signed up for a cooking class at the riad we are staying at. Thus we started the day going out into the medina with the cook and receptionist of the riad to but ingrediants. After that we walked into the new town which is the modern part of Fes. On the way we stopped off at a free vet clinic for donkeys to see if we could have a look around but it was closed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volubilis and Meknes</title>
      <link>/2019/06/06/volubilis-and-meknes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/06/volubilis-and-meknes/</guid>
      <description>I have seen more donkeys in the last couple of days than the rest of my life. We were greeted by a number of them ridden by small children when we stopped off to look at a resevoir on our van ride to Volubilis and Meknes.
Volubis is the ruins of an ancient Roamn city which was very wealthy on account of the large number of olives grown in the area which they pressed to make olive oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eid</title>
      <link>/2019/06/05/eid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/05/eid/</guid>
      <description>Today was a slower day as it is Eid, the day after Ramadan. It is a national holiday and consequently almost everything is closed. We tried to walk to some nearby gardens but they were locked so we wandered around a bit and found the Royal Palace Dar El Makhezen. We took some photos outside its impresive gates but some guards wanted us to move along. We thus walked around its entire perimeter and up a hill to the Marinid Tombs which are some old ruins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touring the Medina</title>
      <link>/2019/06/04/touring-the-medina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/04/touring-the-medina/</guid>
      <description>We started the day with a nice breakfast provided by the Riad we are staying at. Then we got a guide to give us a tour of the Medina. The Medina is the ancient quarter of the city founded 1200 years ago and a UNESCO world heritage site. It is the largest Medina in the world with &amp;gt;9500 small allyways with houses, shops and markets. Unlike other cities the Medina in Fes has not been modernised so cars are not allowed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In transit</title>
      <link>/2019/06/03/in-transit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/03/in-transit/</guid>
      <description>Today was a day in transit. Mark drove us to the Malaga airport and we flew to Bordeaux on Ryanair. We then rechecked my bag and got an AirArabia flight to Fes, Morroco. Both flights were just under 2 hours but all up the travel took all day. Unfortunately my bag was overweight by 4kg so we had to pay to get it on each flight!!
When we got to Fes the airport was very flash and it is noticibly hotter here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mountain</title>
      <link>/2019/06/02/the-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/02/the-mountain/</guid>
      <description>Today Harry wanted to walk up Pico del cielo which is a mountain above Nerja. It is 1508m tall (thats much taller than Ben Nevis the tallest mountain in Britian). It was 3 hours up and 3 hours down and very very steep. In the spanish sun it was very tough but we made it to the top to get some great views over the area. A highlight was an apricot tree growing along the track which had lots of fruit on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>...back to Nerja</title>
      <link>/2019/06/01/back-to-nerja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/01/back-to-nerja/</guid>
      <description>Today we had breakfast at the hotel in the mountains and then drove back to Nerja. We then walked along the beach for an hour or so and went to the restraunt we went to on my first full day here. On the way back Harry, Alex and I walked through the town and went swimming on the sandy beach. The water is very warm. We got ice-cream afterwards.
We went to a fancy restraunt in the evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trevelez</title>
      <link>/2019/05/31/trevelez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/31/trevelez/</guid>
      <description>Today we drove up into the mountains on southern Spain past lots of small villages. We have come to the highest village, Trevelez. This is a very steep town. The main industry is hams so alot of the buildings have large numbers of salted hams drying and the streets smell of ham. We are not sure where the pigs are. We walked up the valley which looked very pretty as the area is a lot more lush than the dry lowlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frigiliana</title>
      <link>/2019/05/30/frigiliana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/30/frigiliana/</guid>
      <description>Today we got the bus up the road to the village of Frigiliana which is an inland village built into the hillside. It is a picturesque village with white buildings and terracotta rooves and lots of small winding (and steep!) streets which are too narrow to drive around. We had a nice lunch (I had black pasta) and walked to the top of the hill overlooking the town. We met some tame donkeys at the top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caves and swimming</title>
      <link>/2019/05/29/caves-and-swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/29/caves-and-swimming/</guid>
      <description>We walked to a neighbouring village called Marro today. The have ancient limestone caves which were inhabited by neaderthals. It was a neat cave complex although unfortunately we didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see any cave paintings as light can destroy them. Nevertheless on the way there we walked past a number of greenhouses growing tomatos, chillies and beans. There are also peach trees, lots of avacados and what looks like sugercane. There are lots of little birds around and I found some quite large frogs in a irigation pond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A day in Nerja</title>
      <link>/2019/05/28/a-day-in-nerja/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/28/a-day-in-nerja/</guid>
      <description>Nothing much to report today. We alked for an hour or so through the town and along the beach and had lunch on the beach. I had a whole fish. Alex and I then wandered through the town a bit more and got ice-cream. I also got a new hat and decent sunscreen. However the heat really sapped my energy and we just laid around all afternoon.
Had dinner at a chinese restraunt tonight which was nice as Harry arrived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the train</title>
      <link>/2019/05/27/on-the-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/27/on-the-train/</guid>
      <description>I got up early today and packed my things and caught the subway across Barcelona to the train station. I had to go through security as it turned out the train I was getting was a high speed one (300 km/h). It was mostly a lot of old people on the train with me but it was a nice train and I could look out the window, read and listen to podcasts for the six hours it took to get to Malaga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romanesque Art</title>
      <link>/2019/05/26/romanesque-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/26/romanesque-art/</guid>
      <description>Today I walked up the hill from my AirBnB to Parc Guell, a failed and unfinished housing estate designed by Gaudi. It was very popular but I am not sure why. It looks like it was the inspiration for Disneyland but is actually quite small with just a few key things to see. While small, it is interesting but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is worthy of its UNESCO World Heritage Site status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Art Nouveau and a maze</title>
      <link>/2019/05/25/art-nouveau-and-a-maze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/25/art-nouveau-and-a-maze/</guid>
      <description>Today I walked to Sant Pau Recinte Modernista which was one of the main hospitals here untill 2009. It was very interesting as its a large complex all in the Art Nouveau style. A lot of thought had been put into how patients should be treated and how the buildings could facilitate that. It was very pretty too. Afterwards I went to Laberint d&amp;rsquo;Horta Park in the north of the city which I think used to be a stately home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rain in Spain ... </title>
      <link>/2019/05/24/the-rain-in-spain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/24/the-rain-in-spain/</guid>
      <description>Turns out the phrase is false and that it does rain in Spain. Neverthless I ventured out and caught the subway to the Gothic Quarter which is the old part of the city with ver narrow streets and allyways. There is an interesting range of shops including a arcade with only pop-culture related stores. There were entire stores related to Harry Potter, Steampunk, Dragonball Z and the Rubics cube. Nevertheless not much opened till 10-11am so I wandered around and found my way to the Parc de la Ciutadella and the Parliament de Catalunya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 29 hours later ... </title>
      <link>/2019/05/23/over-29-hours-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/23/over-29-hours-later/</guid>
      <description>Finally arrived after a very long trip. I didn&amp;rsquo;t end up having much time in either Sydney or Dubai but overall the flights were ok and I watched a few movies. Mostly about women trying to change their boyfriends and it not working. Anyway, I got to Barcelona and got a bus to the centre of town. I then got the subway to the AirBnB I am staying at. The woman here is very nice and helpful and the area looks interesting to walk around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving Auckland</title>
      <link>/2019/05/22/leaving-auckland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/22/leaving-auckland/</guid>
      <description>Good-bye Auckland! Barcelona here I come!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>